You can erase someone from your mind. Getting them
out of your heart is another story.
Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind is a science fiction,
drama, romance film directed by Michel Gondry.
Joel Barish, heartbroken that his girlfriend underwent a procedure to
erase him from her memory, decides to do the same.
However, as he watches his memories of her fade away, he realises that he
still loves her, and may be too late to correct his mistake.
Joel Barish, played by Jim Carrey.
Clementine Kruczynski, played by Kate Winslet.
Mary, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Stan, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Patrick, played by Elijah Wood.
Dr. Mierzwiak, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind is a 2004 American romantic drama film directed by Michel Gondry
and written by Charlie Kaufman from a story by Gondry, Kaufman, and Pierre Bismuth.
It stars Jim Carrey and Kate Winslet as a couple who
undergo memory erasure after they break up.
Kirsten Dunst, Mark Ruffalo, Elijah Wood and Tom
Wilkinson appear in supporting roles.
The title of the film is a quotation from the 1717 poem
Eloisa to Abelard by Alexander Pope.
It uses elements of psychological drama and science fiction and a
nonlinear narrative to explore the nature of memory and love.
Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind was released in theaters in the United States by Focus Features on
March 19, 2004, to widespread acclaim from critics, who praised the script and direction.
The film was a box office success, grossing $74 million on a $20 million budget, and was
named by the American Film Institute one of the Top 10 Films of 2004.
At the 77th Academy Awards, Bismuth, Gondry and Kaufman won Best Original
Screenplay, and Winslet received a nomination for Best Actress.
The film has been named by several publications as one of the
greatest of the 21st century and gained a cult following.
It was the inspiration behind several music projects, such as Jay Electronica's 2007 piece "Eternal Sunshine (The
Pledge)", Jhené Aiko's 2014 track "Spotless Mind" and Ariana Grande's 2024 album Eternal Sunshine.
The film explores themes of new york city, regret, jealousy, deja vu, amnesia.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and mind_bending.